Today's Puja is a very great Puja for Me,
Bugünün pujasının benim için değeri çok büyük,
because I suddenly find that My granddaughter is missing,
çünkü birdenbire fark ettim ki, torunum kayıp
and I got upset with it very much.
ve bu beni çok endişelendirdi.
Look at Me, supposed to be Adi Shakti,
Bana bakın, Ben Adi Shakti'yim,
and why should I get so upset about My granddaughter missing?
torunumun kaybolması Beni nasıl bu kadar telaşlandırıyor?
It was just a human nature,
İşte bu insan doğası
which I realized all of us have.
ve fark ettim ki hepimiz buna sahibiz.
If we have some responsibility
Eğer bir sorumluluğumuz varsa
and we are not there, we get upset.
ve yerine getiremezsek rahatsız oluruz.
Thank God there are very few children here,
Allah'a şükür burada çok fazla çocuk yok,
most of them have gone.
bir çoğu gitti.
But we are all children
Fakat endişelenme şeklimizle,
the way we worry, the way we are anxious.
tasalı olma biçimimizle aslında bizler hepimiz çocuğuz.
Today I would like all of you to say
Bugün size söylemek isterim ki,
that a New Year has come.
yeni bir yıl geldi.
And in this New Year we all should have
Ve bu yeni yılda hepimizin kendimizle ilgili
a new proposal about ourselves.
yeni planlarımız olmalı.
And that proposal is very difficult for people to make out
Bu planda; hiç bir kimse için
- that we are not responsible for anyone.
sorumlu olmadığımızı anlayabilmek çok zor.
We are our own, and we live with ourselves.
Kendi kendimizeyiz ve kendi kendimizle yaşıyoruz.
It's very difficult.
Bunu anlamak çok zor.
Of course those who have no children
Elbette ki, çocukları olmayanlar
are very happy people that way.
çok mutlu  -bir şekilde-
But those who have,
diğerleri belirli sorumlulukları olanlar,
those who have certain responsibilities
belirli bağlılıkları,
and commitments they are still hanging in the air.
hala havada sallanıyorlar
They are nowhere near Sahaja Yoga, I must say.
Ve söylemeliyim ki, Sahaja Yoganın yakınında değiller.
Our main responsibility is ourselves,
Esas sorumluluğumuz kendimiziz,
is to know ourselves
kendimizi bilmek
and to depend on ourselves.
ve kendimize güvenmek.
It is a very big responsibility,
Bu çok büyük bir sorumluluk,
because now as we will be having big functions
çünkü büyük işlerimiz olduğunda,
and we might feel that we are lost in it.
onun içinde kaybolabiliriz.
Please, try to remember
Lütfen, kendinizi hatırlamak
that  you have to remember your Self.
zorunda olduğunuzu hatırlamaya çalışın.
You have to know that you are there.
Kendiniz olduğunu bilmelisiniz.
That's the message I wanted to give you.
Bugün size vermek istediğim mesaj bu.
I hope you'll think it over.
Umarım bunun üzerinde düşünürsünüz.
May God bless you all!
Tanrı sizi kutsasın.